So here I'll show you how to interact with
所以这里我会告诉你如何与
a car object that can keep track of its own state.
一个能跟踪自己状态的汽车对象进行交互
First, you'll see some import statements
首先 你会看到一些 import 语句
and some code that we'll go through in detail soon.
以及我们稍后详细介绍的一些代码
But before we dive into the code that makes up an object,
但在我们深入学习构成对象的代码之前
we'll learn how to interact with it.
我们将学习如何与之进行交互
So next you'll see some initial variables.
接下来你会看到一些初始变量
First a world, and then some variables that should look familiar,
首先是一个世界 然后是一些应该看起来很熟悉的变量
and initial position and velocity.
和初始位置和速度
This time, the position is in two dimensions, Y and X,
这一次 初始位置是二维的 Y 和 X
and the velocity is also broken down into vertical and horizontal components VY and VX.
并且速度也被分解成垂直和水平分量 VY 和 VX
I'll make sure to run both of these,
我会确保运行这两个
then to create a car which I'll name Carla.
然后创建一辆我会命名为 Carla 的汽车
I have to say car_dot_car and pass in some initial state.
我必须输入car_dot_car 并输入初始状态
So I'm passing in some YX position and velocity.
这里 我输入了 YX 位置和速率
And lastly I'm passing in a world which is just a 2D array,
最后 我正在输入的只是一个由二维数组表示的世界
and I'll print out Carla's initial state.
然后我将输出 Carla 的初始位置
You'll notice that I can access Carla's state by saying Carla_dot_state,
你会注意到 我可以通过 Carla_dot_state 来访问 Carla 的状态
and we see that the initial position is at zero zero,
我们看到初始位置为 00
and the initial velocity is zero one,
初始速度为 01
which means it has some horizontal velocity to the right.
这意味着它在右侧有一些水平速度
Now this car object,
现在这辆车对象
Carla, has some visualization code too.
Carla 也有一些可视化代码
And we can see where the car is at any given point using the display world function.
我们可以使用显示世界功能来查看汽车在任何给定点的位置
I can say Carla_dot_display_world,
我可以运行 Carla_dot_display_world
and when I run this code,
当我运行这个代码时
I'll see the location of Carla and the size of the 2D world.
我会看到 Carla 的位置和二维世界的大小
Now, what else can Carla do?
Carla 还可以做什么呢？
Well, we can tell Carla to move by saying Carla_dot_move,
我们可以通过 Carla_dot_move 来告诉 Carla 开始移动
and Carla will move one grid cell in the direction of the initial velocity,
然后 Carla 将沿着初始速度的方向移动一个网格单元
which in this case is towards the right.
在这种情况下 就是向右移动
Let's test this movement by displaying the world again,
我们可以看到 Carla 向右移动了一个网格单元
and we can see that Carla has moved one space to the right.
在移动后 我们也可以跟踪 Carla 状态的变化
After this movement, we can also track the change in Carla's state,
我可以再次使用 Carla_dot_state 输出这个值
and I can print out its value using Carla_dot_state again.
我们可以看到这个状态实际上已经更新
And we can see that the state has actually updated.
该位置已经向右移动了一个网格单元
The position has moved one grid cell to the right,
并且速度保持恒定
and the velocity remains constant.
所以 Carla 正在跟踪自己的状态
So somehow Carla is keeping track of her own state.
如果我们再移动几次呢？
And what if we move a couple more times?
我们来跟踪状态的变化
Let's track the change in state,
我们看到 已经向右移动了两个网格单元 zero_comma_three
and we see that we've moved two more to the right, zero_comma_three.
我们可以看到世界地图上的移动
And we can see the movement on a map of the world by
通过再次调用 Carla_dot_display_world
calling Carla_dot_display_world once more.
所以我们能自动地知道 Carla 的状态更新
So we know Carla's state updates automatically.
Carla 也可以左转
Carla can also turn left.
现在 我们告诉 Carla 左转 并移动一个网格单元
So let's tell Carla to turn left and move one space.
让我们来展示这个世界
And let's display the world.
我们可以看到 Carla 在这个点左转 实际上是在环绕这个世界
We can see that Carla turns left at this spot and actually circles around the world.
如果我们通过将 Carla_state 改为字符串 Carla_dot_state 来输出 Carla 的状态
And if we print out Carla's state by saying Carla_state is string Carla_dot_state,
我们可以看到位置和速度都发生了变化
we see that both the position and the velocity have changed.
我们的位置是 3_3
Our position is three_three,
这反映在单元格中
which is reflected in our grid,
VY 现在是负_一 VX 是零
and VY is now negative_one and VX is zero.
这意味着没有水平速度
This means that there is no horizontal velocity,
只有负的垂直速度
there's only a negative vertical velocity,
这意味着 Carla 在我们的网格世界向上移动
which means Carla's moving up our grid world.
现在Carla 只能移动和左转
Now moving and turning left are all Carla can do for now,
但是我们很快就学习 如何赋予其新功能